[
  {
    "id": 345,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( m ^ 4 q ^ 4 z ^ - 1 ) ( m q ^ 5 z ^3)$$ , where $$m$$ , $$q$$ , and $$z$$ are positive?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$m ^ 4 q ^ 20 z ^ - 3$$",
      "B) $$m ^ 5 q ^ 9 z ^2$$",
      "C) $$m ^ 6 q ^ 8 z ^ - 1$$",
      "D) $$m ^ 20 q ^ 12 z ^ - 2$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Applying the commutative property of multiplication, the expression $$( m ^ 4  q ^ 4  z ^ - 1  ) ( m q ^ 5  z ^3)$$ can be rewritten as $$( m ^ 4  m ) ( q ^ 4  q ^ 5  ) ( z ^ - 1  z ^3)$$ . For positive values of $$x$$ , $$( x ^ a  ) ( x ^ b  ) = x ^ a + b$$ . Therefore, the expression $$( m ^ 4  m ) ( q ^ 4  q ^ 5  ) ( z ^ - 1  z ^3)$$ can be rewritten as $$( m ^ 4 + 1  ) ( q ^ 4 + 5  ) ( z ^ - 1 + 3 )$$ , or $$m ^ 5  q ^ 9  z ^2$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from multiplying, not adding, the exponents. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 353,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{8 x ( x - 7 ) - 3 ( x - 7 )}{2 x - 14}$$ , where $$x > 7$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{x - 7}{5}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{8 x - 3}{2}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{8 x ^2 - 3 x - 14}{2 x - 14}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{8 x ^2 - 3 x - 77}{2 x - 14}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression has a common factor of 2 in the denominator, so the expression can be rewritten as $$\\frac{8 x ( x - 7 ) - 3 ( x - 7 )}{2 ( x - 7 )}$$ . The three terms in this expression have a common factor of $$( x - 7)$$ . Since it's given that $$x > 7$$ , $$x$$ can't be equal to 7 , which means $$( x - 7)$$ can't be equal to 0 . Therefore, each term in the expression, $$\\frac{8 x ( x - 7 ) - 3 ( x - 7 )}{2 ( x - 7 )}$$ , can be divided by $$( x - 7)$$ , which gives $$\\frac{8 x - 3}{2}$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 370,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "Which of the following expressions is(are) a factor of $$3 x ^2 + 20 x - 63$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) I only",
      "B) II only",
      "C) I and II",
      "D) Neither I nor II"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression can be factored by first finding two values whose sum is 20 and whose product is $$3 ( - 63)$$ , or $$- 189$$ . Those two values are 27 and $$- 7$$ . It follows that the given expression can be rewritten as $$3 x ^2 + 27 x - 7 x - 63$$ . Since the first two terms of this expression have a common factor of $$3 x$$ and the last two terms of this expression have a common factor of $$- 7$$ , this expression can be rewritten as $$3 x ( x + 9 ) - 7 ( x + 9)$$ . Since the two terms of this expression have a common factor of $$( x + 9)$$ , it can be rewritten as $$( 3 x - 7 ) ( x + 9)$$ . Therefore, expression II, $$3 x - 7$$ , is a factor of $$3 x ^2 + 20 x - 63$$ , but expression I, $$x - 9$$ , is not a factor of $$3 x ^2 + 20 x - 63$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 382,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": false,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "The expression $$90 y ^ 5 - 54 y ^ 4$$ is equivalent to $$r y ^ 4 ( 15 y - 9)$$ , where $$r$$ is a constant. What is the value of $$r$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [],
    "correctAnswer": "6",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 6 . Applying the distributive property to the expression $$r y ^ 4  ( 15 y - 9)$$ yields $$15 r y ^ 5 - 9 r y ^ 4$$ . Since $$90 y ^ 5 - 54 y ^ 4$$ is equivalent to $$r y ^ 4  ( 15 y - 9)$$ , it follows that $$90 y ^ 5 - 54 y ^ 4$$ is also equivalent to $$15 r y ^ 5 - 9 r y ^ 4$$ . Since these expressions are equivalent, it follows that corresponding coefficients are equivalent. Therefore, $$90 = 15 r$$ and $$- 54 = - 9 r$$ . Solving either of these equations for $$r$$ will yield the value of $$r$$ . Dividing both sides of $$90 = 15 r$$ by 15 yields $$6 = r$$ . Therefore, the value of $$r$$ is 6 .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 398,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$11 x ^3 - 5 x ^3$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$16 x ^3$$",
      "B) $$6 x ^3$$",
      "C) $$6 x ^ 6$$",
      "D) $$16 x ^ 6$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression can be rewritten as $$11 x ^3 + ( - 5 ) x ^3$$ . Since the two terms of this expression are both constant multiples of $$x ^3$$ , they are like terms and can, therefore, be combined through addition. Adding like terms in the expression $$11 x ^3 + ( - 5 ) x ^3$$ yields $$6 x ^3$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This is equivalent to $$11 x ^3 + 5 x ^3$$ , not $$11 x ^3 - 5 x ^3$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This is equivalent to $$11 x ^ 6 - 5 x ^ 6$$ , not $$11 x ^3 - 5 x ^3$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This is equivalent to $$11 x ^ 6 + 5 x ^ 6$$ , not $$11 x ^3 - 5 x ^3$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 399,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$50 x ^2 + 5 x ^2$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$250 x ^2$$",
      "B) $$10 x ^2$$",
      "C) $$45 x ^2$$",
      "D) $$55 x ^2$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. The given expression shows addition of two like terms. Therefore, the given expression is equivalent to $$( 50 + 5 ) x ^2$$ , or $$55 x ^2$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 50 ) ( 5 ) x ^2$$ , not $$( 50 + 5 ) x ^2$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( \\frac{50}{5} ) x ^2$$ , not $$( 50 + 5 ) x ^2$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 50 - 5 ) x ^2$$ , not $$( 50 + 5 ) x ^2$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 402,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$20 w - ( 4 w + 3 w)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": ["A) $$10 w$$", "B) $$13 w$$", "C) $$19 w$$", "D) $$21 w$$"],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Combining like terms inside the parentheses of the given expression, $$20 w - ( 4 w + 3 w)$$ , yields $$20 w - ( 7 w)$$ . Combining like terms in this resulting expression yields $$13 w$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 403,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{4}{4 x - 5} - \\frac{1}{x + 1}$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{1}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{3}{3 x - 6}$$",
      "C) $$- \\frac{1}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{9}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. The expression $$\\frac{4}{4 x - 5} - \\frac{1}{x + 1}$$ can be rewritten as $$\\frac{4}{4 x - 5} + \\frac{( - 1 )}{x + 1}$$ . To add the two terms of this expression, the terms can be rewritten with a common denominator. Since $$\\frac{x + 1}{x + 1} = 1$$ , the expression $$\\frac{4}{4 x - 5}$$ can be rewritten as $$\\frac{( x + 1 ) ( 4 )}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$ . Since $$\\frac{4 x - 5}{4 x - 5} = 1$$ , the expression $$\\frac{negative 1}{x + 1}$$ can be rewritten as $$\\frac{( 4 x - 5 ) ( - 1 )}{( 4 x - 5 ) ( x + 1 )}$$ . Therefore, the expression $$\\frac{4}{4 x - 5} + \\frac{( - 1 )}{x + 1}$$ can be rewritten as $$\\frac{( x + 1 ) ( 4 )}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )} + \\frac{( 4 x - 5 ) ( - 1 )}{( 4 x - 5 ) ( x + 1 )}$$ , which is equivalent to $$\\frac{( x + 1 ) ( 4 ) + ( 4 x - 5 ) ( - 1 )}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$ . Applying the distributive property to each term of the numerator yields $$\\frac{( 4 x + 4 ) + ( - 4 x + 5 )}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$ , or $$\\frac{( 4 x + ( - 4 x ) ) + ( 4 + 5 )}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$ . Adding like terms in the numerator yields $$\\frac{9}{( x + 1 ) ( 4 x - 5 )}$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 417,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( d - 6 ) ( 8 d ^2 - 3)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$8 d ^3 - 14 d ^2 - 3 d + 18$$",
      "B) $$8 d ^3 - 17 d ^2 + 48$$",
      "C) $$8 d ^3 - 48 d ^2 - 3 d + 18$$",
      "D) $$8 d ^3 - 51 d ^2 + 48$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "C",
    "explanation": "Choice C is correct. Applying the distributive property to the given expression yields $$d ( 8 d ^2 - 3 ) - 6 ( 8 d ^2 - 3)$$ . Applying the distributive property once again to this expression yields $$( d ) ( 8 d ^2 ) + ( d ) ( - 3 ) + ( - 6 ) ( 8 d ^2 ) + ( - 6 ) ( - 3)$$ , or $$8 d ^3 + ( - 3 d ) + ( - 48 d ^2 ) + 18$$ . This expression can be rewritten as $$8 d ^3 - 48 d ^2 - 3 d + 18$$ . Thus, $$( d - 6 ) ( 8 d ^2 - 3)$$ is equivalent to $$8 d ^3 - 48 d ^2 - 3 d + 18$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 451,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "The expression $$\\frac{24}{6 x + 42}$$ is equivalent to $$\\frac{4}{x + b}$$ , where b is a constant and $$x > 0$$ . What is the value of b ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": ["A) $$7$$", "B) $$10$$", "C) $$24$$", "D) $$252$$"],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. Since the given expressions are equivalent and the numerator of the second expression is $$one sixth$$ of the numerator of the first expression, the denominator of the second expression must also be $$one sixth$$ of the denominator of the first expression. By the distributive property, $$one sixth ( 6 x + 42)$$ is equivalent to $$one sixth ( 6 x ) + one sixth ( 42)$$ , or $$x + 7$$ . Therefore, the value of $$b$$ is 7 . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 465,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "The expression $$4 x ^2 + b x - 45$$ , where $$b$$ is a constant, can be rewritten as $$( h x + k ) ( x + j)$$ , where $$h$$ , $$k$$ , and $$j$$ are integer constants. Which of the following must be an integer?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{b}{h}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{b}{k}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{45}{h}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{45}{k}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. It's given that $$4 x ^2 + b x - 45$$ can be rewritten as $$( h x + k ) ( x + j)$$ . The expression $$( h x + k ) ( x + j)$$ can be rewritten as $$h x ^2 + j h x + k x + k j$$ , or $$h x ^2 + ( j h + k ) x + k j$$ . Therefore, $$h x ^2 + ( j h + k ) x + k j$$ is equivalent to $$4 x ^2 + b x - 45$$ . It follows that $$k j = - 45$$ . Dividing each side of this equation by $$k$$ yields $$j = \\frac{negative 45}{k}$$ . Since $$j$$ is an integer, $$- \\frac{45}{k}$$ must be an integer. Therefore, $$\\frac{45}{k}$$ must also be an integer. Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 468,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is a factor of $$2 x ^2 + 38 x + 10$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": ["A) $$2$$", "B) $$5 x$$", "C) $$38 x$$", "D) $$2 x ^2$$"],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. Since 2 is a common factor of each of the terms in the given expression, the expression can be rewritten as $$2 ( x ^2 + 19 x + 5)$$ . Therefore, the factors of the given expression are 2 and $$x ^2 + 19 x + 5$$ . Of these two factors, only 2 is listed as a choice. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect. This is a term of the given expression, not a factor of the given expression. Choice D is incorrect. This is a term of the given expression, not a factor of the given expression.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 497,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( 7 x ^3 + 7 x ) - ( 6 x ^3 - 3 x)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$x ^3 + 10 x$$",
      "B) $$- 13 x ^3 + 10 x$$",
      "C) $$- 13 x ^3 + 4 x$$",
      "D) $$x ^3 + 4 x$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. Applying the distributive property, the given expression can be written as $$7 x ^3 + 7 x - 6 x ^3 + 3 x$$ . Grouping like terms in this expression yields $$( 7 x ^3 - 6 x ^3 ) + ( 7 x + 3 x)$$ . Combining like terms in this expression yields $$x ^3 + 10 x$$ . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 506,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$6 x ^ 8 y ^2 + 12 x ^2 y ^2$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( 2 x ^ 6 )$$",
      "B) $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( x ^ 4 )$$",
      "C) $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( x ^ 6 + 2)$$",
      "D) $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( x ^ 4 + 2)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "C",
    "explanation": "Choice C is correct. Since each term of the given expression has a common factor of $$6 x ^2 y ^2$$ , it may be rewritten as $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( x ^ 6  ) + 6 x ^2 y ^2 ( 2)$$ , or $$6 x ^2 y ^2 ( x ^ 6  + 2)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$12 x ^ 8  y ^2$$ , not $$6 x ^ 8  y ^2 + 12 x ^2 y ^2$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$6 x ^ 6  y ^2$$ , not $$6 x ^ 8  y ^2 + 12 x ^2 y ^2$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$6 x ^ 6  y ^2 + 12 x ^2 y ^2$$ , not $$6 x ^ 8  y ^2 + 12 x ^2 y ^2$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 513,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$a ^ \\frac{11}{12}$$ , where $$a > 0$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\sqrt[12]{ a ^ 132 }$$",
      "B) $$\\sqrt[144]{ a ^ 132 }$$",
      "C) $$\\sqrt[121]{ a ^ 132 }$$",
      "D) $$\\sqrt[11]{ a ^ 132 }$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Since $$\\frac{12}{12} = 1$$ , multiplying the exponent of the given expression by $$\\frac{12}{12}$$ yields an equivalent expression: $$a ^ ( \\frac{11}{12} ) ( \\frac{12}{12} )  = a ^ ( \\frac{132}{144})$$ . Since $$\\frac{132}{144} = 132 ( \\frac{1}{144})$$ , the expression $$a ^ \\frac{132}{144}$$ can be rewritten as $$a ^ ( 132 ) ( \\frac{1}{144})$$ . Applying properties of exponents, this expression can be rewritten as $$( a ^ 132  ) ^ \\frac{1}{144}$$ . An expression of the form $$( m ) ^ \\frac{1}{k}$$ , where $$m > 0$$ and $$k > 0$$ , is equivalent to $$RootIndex k \\sqrt{ m}$$ . Therefore, $$( a ^ 132  ) ^ \\frac{1}{144}$$ is equivalent to $$RootIndex 144 \\sqrt{ a ^ 132 }$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 528,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$9 x ^2 + 5 x$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$x ( 9 x + 5)$$",
      "B) $$5 x ( 9 x + 1)$$",
      "C) $$9 x ( x + 5)$$",
      "D) $$x ^2 ( 9 x + 5)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. Since $$x$$ is a factor of each term in the given expression, the expression is equivalent to $$x ( 9 x ) + x ( 5)$$ , or $$x ( 9 x + 5)$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$45 x ^2 + 5 x$$ , not $$9 x ^2 + 5 x$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$9 x ^2 + 45 x$$ , not $$9 x ^2 + 5 x$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$9 x ^3 + 5 x ^2$$ , not $$9 x ^2 + 5 x$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 545,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$5 x ^2 - 50 x y ^2$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$5 x ( x - 10 y ^2)$$",
      "B) $$5 x ( x - 50 y ^2)$$",
      "C) $$5 x ^2 ( 10 x y ^2)$$",
      "D) $$5 x ^2 ( 50 x y ^2)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. Since each term of the given expression has a factor of $$5 x$$ , it can be rewritten as $$5 x ( x ) - 5 x ( 10 y ^2)$$ , or $$5 x ( x - 10 y ^2)$$ . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 552,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{y + 12}{x - 8} + \\frac{y ( x - 8 )}{x ^2 y - 8 x y}$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{x y + y + 4}{x ^3 y - 16 x ^2 y + 64 x y}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{x y + 9 y + 12}{x ^2 y - 8 x y + x - 8}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{x y ^2 + 13 x y - 8 y}{x ^2 y - 8 x y}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{x y ^2 + 13 x y - 8 y}{x ^3 y - 16 x ^2 y + 64 x y}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "C",
    "explanation": "Choice C is correct. Factoring the denominator in the second term of the given expression gives $$\\frac{y + 12}{x - 8} + \\frac{y ( x - 8 )}{x y ( x - 8 )}$$ . This expression can be rewritten with common denominators by multiplying the first term by $$\\frac{x y}{x y}$$ , giving $$\\frac{x y ( y + 12 )}{x y ( x - 8 )} + \\frac{y ( x - 8 )}{x y ( x - 8 )}$$ . Adding these two terms yields $$\\frac{x y ( y + 12 ) + y ( x - 8 )}{x y ( x - 8 )}$$ . Using the distributive property to rewrite this expression gives $$\\frac{x y ^2 + 12 x y + x y - 8 y}{x ^2 y - 8 x y}$$ . Combining the like terms in the numerator of this expression gives $$\\frac{x y ^2 + 13 x y - 8 y}{x ^2 y - 8 x y}$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 553,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": false,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "One of the factors of $$2 x ^3 + 42 x ^2 + 208 x$$ is $$x + b$$ , where $$b$$ is a positive constant. What is the smallest possible value of $$b$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [],
    "correctAnswer": "8",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 8 . Since each term of the given expression, $$2 x ^3 + 42 x ^2 + 208 x$$ , has a factor of $$2 x$$ , the expression can be rewritten as $$2 x ( x ^2 ) + 2 x ( 21 x ) + 2 x ( 104)$$ , or $$2 x ( x ^2 + 21 x + 104)$$ . Since the values 8 and 13 have a sum of 21 and a product of 104 , the expression $$x ^2 + 21 x + 104$$ can be factored as $$( x + 8 ) ( x + 13)$$ . Therefore, the given expression can be factored as $$2 x ( x + 8 ) ( x + 13)$$ . It follows that the factors of the given expression are 2 , $$x$$ , $$x + 8$$ , and $$x + 13$$ . Of these factors, only $$x + 8$$ and $$x + 13$$ are of the form $$x + b$$ , where $$b$$ is a positive constant. Therefore, the possible values of $$b$$ are 8 and 13 . Thus, the smallest possible value of $$b$$ is 8 .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 560,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$9 x ^2 + 7 x ^2 + 9 x$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$63 x ^ 4 + 9 x$$",
      "B) $$9 x ^2 + 16 x$$",
      "C) $$25 x ^ 5$$",
      "D) $$16 x ^2 + 9 x$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. In the given expression, the first two terms, $$9 x ^2$$ and $$7 x ^2$$ , are like terms. Combining these like terms yields $$9 x ^2 + 7 x ^2$$ , or $$16 x ^2$$ . It follows that the expression $$9 x ^2 + 7 x ^2 + 9 x$$ is equivalent to $$16 x ^2 + 9 x$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 561,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( 2 x ^2 + x - 9 ) + ( x ^2 + 6 x + 1)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$2 x ^2 + 7 x + 10$$",
      "B) $$2 x ^2 + 6 x - 8$$",
      "C) $$3 x ^2 + 7 x - 10$$",
      "D) $$3 x ^2 + 7 x - 8$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. The given expression is equivalent to $$( 2 x ^2 + x + ( - 9 ) ) + ( x ^2 + 6 x + 1)$$ , which can be rewritten as $$( 2 x ^2 + x ^2 ) + ( x + 6 x ) + ( - 9 + 1)$$ . Adding like terms in this expression yields $$3 x ^2 + 7 x + ( - 8)$$ , or $$3 x ^2 + 7 x - 8$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 570,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": false,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "The expression $$6 \\sqrt[5]{ 3 ^ 5 x ^ 45 } \\cdot   \\sqrt[8]{ 2 ^ 8 x}$$ is equivalent to $$a x ^ b$$ , where $$a$$ and $$b$$ are positive constants and $$x > 1$$ . What is the value of $$a + b$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [],
    "correctAnswer": "361/8",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is $$\\frac{361}{8}$$ . The rational exponent property is $$RootIndex n \\sqrt{ y ^ m  } = y ^ \\frac{m}{n}$$ , where $$y > 0$$ , $$m$$ and $$n$$ are integers, and $$n > 0$$ . This property can be applied to rewrite the given expression $$6 RootIndex 5 \\sqrt{ 3 ^ 5  x ^ 45  } \\cdot RootIndex 8 \\sqrt{ 2 ^ 8  x}$$ as $$6 ( 3 ^ five fifths  ) ( x ^ \\frac{45}{5}  ) ( 2 ^ eight eighths  ) ( x ^ one eighth )$$ , or $$6 ( 3 ) ( x ^ 9  ) ( 2 ) ( x ^ one eighth )$$ . This expression can be rewritten by multiplying the constants, which gives $$36 ( x ^ 9  ) ( x ^ one eighth )$$ . The multiplication exponent property is $$y ^ n  \\cdot y ^ m  = y ^ n + m$$ , where $$y > 0$$ . This property can be applied to rewrite the expression $$36 ( x ^ 9  ) ( x ^ one eighth )$$ as $$36 x ^ 9 + one eighth$$ , or $$36 x ^ \\frac{73}{8}$$ . Therefore, $$6 RootIndex 5 \\sqrt{ 3 ^ 5  x ^ 45  } \\cdot RootIndex 8 \\sqrt{ 2 ^ 8  x } = 36 x ^ \\frac{73}{8}$$ . It's given that $$6 RootIndex 5 \\sqrt{ 3 ^ 5  x ^ 45  } \\cdot RootIndex 8 \\sqrt{ 2 ^ 8  x}$$ is equivalent to $$a x ^ b$$ ; therefore, $$a = 36$$ and $$b = \\frac{73}{8}$$ . It follows that $$a + b = 36 + \\frac{73}{8}$$ . Finding a common denominator on the right-hand side of this equation gives $$a + b = \\frac{288}{8} + \\frac{73}{8}$$ , or $$a + b = \\frac{361}{8}$$ . Note that 361/8, 45.12, and 45.13 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 610,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$8 + d ^2 + 3$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$d ^2 + 24$$",
      "B) $$d ^2 + 11$$",
      "C) $$d ^2 + 5$$",
      "D) $$d ^2 - 11$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression can be rewritten as $$d ^2 + 8 + 3$$ . Adding 8 and 3 in this expression yields $$d ^2 + 11$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$d ^2 + 8 ( 3)$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$8 + d ^2 - 3$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$- 8 + d ^2 - 3$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 616,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": false,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "$$( 5 x ^3 - 3 ) - ( - 4 x ^3 + 8)$$ The given expression is equivalent to $$b x ^3 - 11$$ , where $$b$$ is a constant. What is the value of $$b$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [],
    "correctAnswer": "9",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is 9 . The given expression can be rewritten as $$( 5 x ^3 - 3 ) + ( - 1 ) ( - 4 x ^3 + 8)$$ . By applying the distributive property, this expression can be rewritten as $$5 x ^3 - 3 + 4 x ^3 + ( - 8)$$ , which is equivalent to $$( 5 x ^3 + 4 x ^3 ) + ( - 3 + ( - 8 ))$$ . Adding like terms in this expression yields $$9 x ^3 - 11$$ . Since it's given that $$( 5 x ^3 - 3 ) - ( - 4 x ^3 + 8)$$ is equivalent to $$b x ^3 - 11$$ , it follows that $$9 x ^3 - 11$$ is equivalent to $$b x ^3 - 11$$ . Therefore, the coefficients of $$x ^3$$ in these two expressions must be equivalent, and the value of $$b$$ must be 9 .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 623,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$256 w ^2 - 676$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$( 16 w - 26 ) ( 16 w - 26)$$",
      "B) $$( 8 w - 13 ) ( 8 w + 13)$$",
      "C) $$( 8 w - 13 ) ( 8 w - 13)$$",
      "D) $$( 16 w - 26 ) ( 16 w + 26)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. The given expression follows the difference of two squares pattern, $$x ^2 - y ^2$$ , which factors as $$( x - y ) ( x + y)$$ . Therefore, the expression $$256 w ^2 - 676$$ can be written as $$( 16 w ) ^2 - 26 ^2$$ , or $$( 16 w ) ( 16 w ) - ( 26 ) ( 26)$$ , which factors as $$( 16 w - 26 ) ( 16 w + 26)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$256 w ^2 - 832 w + 676$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$64 w ^2 - 169$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$64 w ^2 - 208 w + 169$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 629,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$ \\sqrt[7]{ x ^ 9 y ^ 9 }$$ , where $$x$$ and $$y$$ are positive?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$( x y ) ^ \\frac{7}{9}$$",
      "B) $$( x y ) ^ \\frac{9}{7}$$",
      "C) $$( x y ) ^ 16$$",
      "D) $$( x y ) ^ 63$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. For positive values of $$a$$ and $$b$$ , $$a ^ m  b ^ m  = ( a b ) ^ m$$ , $$RootIndex n \\sqrt{ a } = ( a ) ^ \\frac{1}{n}$$ , and $$( a ^ j  ) ^ k  = a ^ j k$$ . Therefore, the given expression, $$RootIndex 7 \\sqrt{ x ^ 9  y ^ 9 }$$ , can be rewritten as $$RootIndex 7 \\sqrt{ ( x y ) ^ 9 }$$ . This expression is equivalent to $$( ( x y ) ^ 9  ) ^ one seventh$$ , which can be rewritten as $$( x y ) ^ 9 \\cdot one seventh$$ , or $$( x y ) ^ nine sevenths$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 636,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$12 x ^3 - 5 x ^3$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$7 x ^ 6$$",
      "B) $$17 x ^3$$",
      "C) $$7 x ^3$$",
      "D) $$17 x ^ 6$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "C",
    "explanation": "Choice C is correct. The given expression shows subtraction of two like terms. The two terms can be subtracted as follows: $$12 x ^3 - 5 x ^3 = ( 12 - 5 ) x ^3$$ , or $$7 x ^3$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice B is incorrect. This is the result of adding, not subtracting, the two like terms. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 645,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$x ^2 + 3 x - 40$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$( x - 4 ) ( x + 10)$$",
      "B) $$( x - 5 ) ( x + 8)$$",
      "C) $$( x - 8 ) ( x + 5)$$",
      "D) $$( x - 10 ) ( x + 4)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression may be rewritten as $$x ^2 + 8 x - 5 x - 40$$ . Since the first two terms of this expression have a common factor of $$x$$ and the last two terms of this expression have a common factor of $$- 5$$ , this expression may be rewritten as $$x ( x ) + x ( 8 ) - 5 ( x ) - 5 ( 8)$$ , or $$x ( x + 8 ) - 5 ( x + 8)$$ . Since each term of this expression has a common factor of $$( x + 8)$$ , it may be rewritten as $$( x - 5 ) ( x + 8)$$ . Alternate approach: An expression of the form $$x ^2 + b x + c$$ , where $$b$$ and $$c$$ are constants, can be factored if there are two values that add to give $$b$$ and multiply to give $$c$$ . In the given expression, $$b = 3$$ and $$c = - 40$$ . The values of $$- 5$$ and 8 add to give 3 and multiply to give $$- 40$$ , so the expression can be factored as $$( x - 5 ) ( x + 8)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$x ^2 + 6 x - 40$$ , not $$x ^2 + 3 x - 40$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$x ^2 - 3 x - 40$$ , not $$x ^2 + 3 x - 40$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$x ^2 - 6 x - 40$$ , not $$x ^2 + 3 x - 40$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11615,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$16 x ^3 y ^2 + 14 x y$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$2 x y ( 8 x y + 7)$$",
      "B) $$2 x y ( 8 x ^2 y + 7)$$",
      "C) $$14 x y ( 2 x ^2 y + 1)$$",
      "D) $$14 x y ( 8 x ^2 y + 1)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Since $$2 x y$$ is a common factor of each term in the given expression, the expression can be rewritten as $$2 x y ( 8 x ^2 y + 7)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$16 x ^2 y ^2 + 14 x y$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$28 x ^3 y ^2 + 14 x y$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$112 x ^3 y ^2 + 14 x y$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11626,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which of the following expressions is equivalent to $$8 x ^ 10 - 8 x ^ 9 + 88 x$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$x ( 7 x ^ 10 - 7 x ^ 9 + 87 x)$$",
      "B) $$x ( 8 ^ 10 - 8 ^ 9 + 88)$$",
      "C) $$8 x ( x ^ 10 - x ^ 9 + 11 x)$$",
      "D) $$8 x ( x ^ 9 - x ^ 8 + 11)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. Since $$8 x$$ is a common factor of each term in the given expression, the expression can be rewritten as $$8 x ( x ^ 9  - x ^ 8  + 11)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$7 x ^ 11 - 7 x ^ 10 + 87 x ^2$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$8 ^ 10  x - 8 ^ 9  x + 88 x$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$8 x ^ 11 - 8 x ^ 10 + 88 x ^2$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11627,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( 8 y z ) ( y ) ( 7 z)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$56 y ^2 z ^2$$",
      "B) $$56 y ^2 z$$",
      "C) $$56 y z$$",
      "D) $$16 y z$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. The given expression can be rewritten as $$( 8 \\cdot 7 ) ( y \\cdot y ) ( z \\cdot z)$$ , which is equivalent to $$( 56 ) ( y ^2 ) ( z ^2)$$ , or $$56 y ^2 z ^2$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 8 y z ) ( y ) ( 7)$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 8 z ) ( y ) ( 7)$$ . Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11633,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "$$g ( x ) = \\frac{3}{5}  x + \\frac{7}{6}$$ $$h ( x ) = 6 x - 5$$ The functions $$g$$ and $$h$$ are defined by the equations shown. Which expression is equivalent to $$g ( x ) \\cdot h ( x)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} - \\frac{35}{6}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} + \\frac{27 x}{11} - \\frac{35}{6}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} - 4 x - \\frac{35}{6}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} + 4 x - \\frac{35}{6}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. It’s given that $$g ( x ) = three fifths x + seven sixths$$ and $$h ( x ) = 6 x - 5$$ . Substituting $\\frac{3}{5}$ for $$g ( x)$$ and $$6 x - 5$$ for $$h ( x)$$ in the expression $$g ( x ) \\cdot h ( x)$$ yields $$( three fifths x + seven sixths ) ( 6 x - 5)$$ . This expression can be rewritten as $\\frac{3}{5}$ , or $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} - 3 x + 7 x - \\frac{35}{6}$$ , which is equivalent to $$\\frac{18 x ^2}{5} + 4 x - \\frac{35}{6}$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $\\frac{3}{5}$ , not $$( three fifths x + seven sixths ) ( 6 x - 5)$$ . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( three fifths x - seven sixths ) ( 6 x + 5)$$ , not $$( three fifths x + seven sixths ) ( 6 x - 5)$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11646,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$19 ( x ^2 - 7)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$19 x ^2 - 133$$",
      "B) $$19 x ^2 - 26$$",
      "C) $$19 x ^2 - 7$$",
      "D) $$19 x ^2 + 12$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A",
    "explanation": "Choice A is correct. The expression $$19 ( x ^2 - 7)$$ can be rewritten as $$19 ( x ^2 ) - 19 ( 7)$$ , which is equivalent to $$19 x ^2 - 133$$ . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice D is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11649,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a}{k} + 42 a k$$ , where $$k > 0$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$\\frac{84 a}{k}$$",
      "B) $$\\frac{84 a k ^2}{k}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{42 a ( k + 1 )}{k}$$",
      "D) $$\\frac{42 a ( k ^2 + 1 )}{k}$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. Two fractions can be added together when they have a common denominator. Since $$k > 0$$ , multiplying the second term in the given expression by $$\\frac{k}{k}$$ yields $$\\frac{( 42 a k ) k}{k}$$ , which is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a k ^2}{k}$$ . Therefore, the expression $$\\frac{42 a}{k} + 42 a k$$ can be written as $$\\frac{42 a}{k} + \\frac{42 a k ^2}{k}$$ which is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a + 42 a k ^2}{k}$$ . Since each term in the numerator of this expression has a factor of $$42 a$$ , the expression $$\\frac{42 a + 42 a k ^2}{k}$$ can be rewritten as $$\\frac{42 a ( 1 ) + 42 a ( k ^2 )}{k}$$ , or $$\\frac{42 a ( 1 + k ^2 )}{k}$$ , which is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a ( k ^2 + 1 )}{k}$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a}{k} + \\frac{42 a}{k}$$ . Choice B is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$\\frac{42 a}{k} + 42 a$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11662,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": false,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "If $$4 ^ 8 c =  \\sqrt[3]{ 4 ^ 7 }$$ , what is the value of $$c$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [],
    "correctAnswer": ".2916",
    "explanation": "The correct answer is $$seven twenty fourths$$ . An expression of the form $$RootIndex n \\sqrt{ a ^ m }$$ , where $$m$$ and $$n$$ are integers greater than 1 and $$a > \\lor = 0$$ , is equivalent to $$a ^ \\frac{m}{n}$$ . Therefore, the expression on the right-hand side of the given equation, $$RootIndex 3 \\sqrt{ 4 ^ 7 }$$ , is equivalent to $$4 ^ seven thirds$$ . Thus, $$4 ^ 8 c  = 4 ^ seven thirds$$ . It follows that $$8 c = seven thirds$$ . Dividing both sides of this equation by 8 yields $$c = seven twenty fourths$$ . Note that 7/24, .2916, .2917, 0.219, and 0.292 are examples of ways to enter a correct answer.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11669,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$5 x ^ 5 - 6 x ^ 4 + 8 x ^3$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$x ^ 4 ( 5 x - 6)$$",
      "B) $$x ^3 ( 5 x ^2 - 6 x + 8)$$",
      "C) $$8 x ^3 ( 5 x ^2 - 6 x + 1)$$",
      "D) $$6 x ^ 5 ( - 6 x ^ 4 + 8 x ^3 + 1)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Since $$x ^3$$ is a common factor of each term in the given expression, the expression can be rewritten as $$x ^3 ( 5 x ^2 - 6 x + 8)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$5 x ^ 5 - 6 x ^ 4$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$40 x ^ 5 - 48 x ^ 4 + 8 x ^3$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$- 36 x ^ 9 + 48 x ^ 8 + 6 x ^ 5$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11671,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( x ^2 + 11 ) ^2 + ( x - 5 ) ( x + 5)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$x ^ 4 + 23 x ^2 - 14$$",
      "B) $$x ^ 4 + 23 x ^2 + 96$$",
      "C) $$x ^ 4 + 12 x ^2 + 121$$",
      "D) $$x ^ 4 + x ^2 + 146$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The expression $$( x ^2 + 11 ) ^2$$ can be written as $$( x ^2 + 11 ) ( x ^2 + 11)$$ , which is equivalent to $$x ^2 ( x ^2 + 11 ) + 11 ( x ^2 + 11)$$ . Distributing $$x ^2$$ and 11 to $$( x ^2 + 11)$$ yields $$x ^ 4  + 11 x ^2 + 11 x ^2 + 121$$ , or $$x ^ 4  + 22 x ^2 + 121$$ . The expression $$( x - 5 ) ( x + 5)$$ is equivalent to $$( x - 5 ) x + ( x - 5 ) 5$$ . Distributing $$x$$ and 5 to $$( x - 5)$$ yields $$x ^2 - 5 x + 5 x - 25$$ , or $$x ^2 - 25$$ . Therefore, the expression $$( x ^2 + 11 ) ^2 + ( x - 5 ) ( x + 5)$$ is equivalent to $$( x ^ 4  + 22 x ^2 + 121 ) + ( x ^2 - 25)$$ , or $$x ^ 4  + 22 x ^2 + 121 + x ^2 - 25$$ . Combining like terms in this expression yields $$x ^ 4  + 23 x ^2 + 96$$ . Choice A is incorrect. Equivalent expressions must be equivalent for any value of $$x$$ . Substituting 0 for $$x$$ in this expression yields $$- 14$$ , whereas substituting 0 for $$x$$ in the given expression yields 96 . Choice C is incorrect. Equivalent expressions must be equivalent for any value of $$x$$ . Substituting 0 for $$x$$ in this expression yields 121 , whereas substituting 0 for $$x$$ in the given expression yields 96 . Choice D is incorrect. Equivalent expressions must be equivalent for any value of $$x$$ . Substituting 0 for $$x$$ in this expression yields 146 , whereas substituting 0 for $$x$$ in the given expression yields 96 .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11677,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( x ^3 - 2)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$8 x ^3 + 6$$",
      "B) $$7 x ^3 + 10$$",
      "C) $$8 x ^3 + 10$$",
      "D) $$7 x ^3 + 6$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. The given expression is equivalent to $$8 x ^3 + 8 - x ^3 - ( - 2)$$ , or $$8 x ^3 + 8 - x ^3 + 2$$ . Combining like terms in this expression yields $$7 x ^3 + 10$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - 2$$ , not $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( x ^3 - 2)$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( - 2)$$ , not $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( x ^3 - 2)$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( x ^3 + 2)$$ , not $$( 8 x ^3 + 8 ) - ( x ^3 - 2)$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11691,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "question": "If $$k - x$$ is a factor of the expression $$- x ^2 + \\frac{1}{29} n k ^2$$ , where $$n$$ and $$k$$ are constants and $$k > 0$$ , what is the value of $$n$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$- 29$$",
      "B) $$- \\frac{1}{29}$$",
      "C) $$\\frac{1}{29}$$",
      "D) $$29$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. If $$k - x$$ is a factor of the expression $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ , then the expression can be written as $$( k - x ) ( a x + b)$$ , where $$a$$ and $$b$$ are constants. This expression can be rewritten as $$a k x + b k - a x ^2 - b x$$ , or $$- a x ^2 + ( a k - b ) x + b k$$ . Since this expression is equivalent to $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ , it follows that $$- a = - 1$$ , $$a k - b = 0$$ , and $$b k = ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ . Dividing each side of the equation $$- a = - 1$$ by $$- 1$$ yields $$a = 1$$ . Substituting 1 for $$a$$ in the equation $$a k - b = 0$$ yields $$k - b = 0$$ . Adding $$b$$ to each side of this equation yields $$k = b$$ . Substituting $$k$$ for $$b$$ in the equation $$b k = ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ yields $$k ^2 = ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ . Since $$k$$ is positive, dividing each side of this equation by $$k ^2$$ yields $$1 = ( one twenty ninth ) n$$ . Multiplying each side of this equation by 29 yields $$29 = n$$ . Alternate approach: The expression $$x ^2 - y ^2$$ can be written as $$( x - y ) ( x + y)$$ , which is a difference of two squares. It follows that $$( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2 - x ^2$$ is equivalent to $$( ( \\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } ) k - x ) ( ( \\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } ) k + x)$$ . It’s given that $$k - x$$ is a factor of $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) n k ^2$$ , so the factor $$( \\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } ) k - x$$ is equal to $$k - x$$ . Adding $$x$$ to both sides of the equation $$( \\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } ) k - x = k - x$$ yields $$( \\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } ) k = k$$ . Since $$k$$ is positive, dividing both sides of this equation by $$k$$ yields $$\\sqrt{ one twenty ninth n } = 1$$ . Squaring both sides of this equation yields $$one twenty ninth n = 1$$ . Multiplying both sides of this equation by 29 yields $$n = 29$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This value of $$n$$ gives the expression $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) ( - 29 ) k ^2$$ , or $$- x ^2 - k ^2$$ . This expression doesn't have $$k - x$$ as a factor. Choice B is incorrect. This value of $$n$$ gives the expression $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) ( - one twenty ninth ) k ^2$$ , or $$- x ^2 + ( - \\frac{1}{841} ) k ^2$$ . This expression doesn't have $$k - x$$ as a factor. Choice C is incorrect. This value of $$n$$ gives the expression $$- x ^2 + ( one twenty ninth ) ( one twenty ninth ) k ^2$$ , or $$- x ^2 + ( \\frac{1}{841} ) k ^2$$ . This expression doesn't have $$k - x$$ as a factor.",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11692,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$17 ( x - 2 y ) ( x - 50 y)$$",
      "B) $$17 ( x - 2 y ) ( x + 50 y)$$",
      "C) $$17 ( x - 10 y ) ( x - 10 y)$$",
      "D) $$17 ( x - 10 y ) ( x + 10 y)$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "D",
    "explanation": "Choice D is correct. Expressions in the form $$a ^2 - b ^2$$ follow the difference of two squares pattern and can be factored as $$( a - b ) ( a + b)$$ . In the given expression, $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ , the expression $$x ^2 - 100 y ^2$$ follows the difference of two squares pattern. It follows that the expression $$x ^2 - 100 y ^2$$ can be rewritten as $$( x - 10 y ) ( x + 10 y)$$ . Therefore, the expression $$17 ( x - 10 y ) ( x + 10 y)$$ is equivalent to $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ . Choice A is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$17 ( x ^2 - 52 x y + 100 y ^2)$$ , not $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ . Choice B is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$17 ( x ^2 + 48 x y - 100 y ^2)$$ , not $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ . Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$17 ( x ^2 - 20 x y + 100 y ^2)$$ , not $$17 ( x ^2 - 100 y ^2)$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  },
  {
    "id": 11694,
    "type": "Math",
    "is_multiple_choice": true,
    "topic": "Advanced Math",
    "subtopic": "Equivalent Expressions",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "question": "Which expression is equivalent to $$34 x + 34 y$$ ?",
    "passage": "",
    "choices": [
      "A) $$34 x y$$",
      "B) $$34 ( x + y)$$",
      "C) $$68 y$$",
      "D) $$68 x$$"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "B",
    "explanation": "Choice B is correct. Since 34 is a common factor of each term in the given expression, the expression can be rewritten as $$34 ( x + y)$$ . Choice A is incorrect and may result from conceptual or calculation errors. Choice C is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$34 y + 34 y$$ . Choice D is incorrect. This expression is equivalent to $$34 x + 34 x$$ .",
    "solveRate": 30,
    "bluebook": true,
    "html_table": "",
    "svg_image": ""
  }
]
